Mobile: 09913360320 Email: vir070784@gmail.com Ahmedabad, Gujarat.-380008.

Accomplished in Accounts with 16+ Year of Experience in Accounts and Finance

OBJECTIVE

In Accounts, where skills can be put to the benefit of the company utilizing my experience in Accounting with a flare of Strategy and Planning in Accounts field, along with personal Growth.

CAREER SUMMARY

Excellent knowledge of the statutory compliances pertaining to financial services sector, proficient in auditing and accounting

Strong focus on management requirements, customer service and satisfaction Experienced in forecasting and managing cash and funds flow and in ensuing smooth operations Performance oriented and recipient of promotion for excellence.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Asst. Manager - Account & Finance, Cama Hotels Limited, May 2018 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Working with IDS (Internet Distribution System) Hotel management software.
- Prepares and records revenue and expenses entries by compiling account information
- Maintains general ledger by transferring subsidiary accounts & reconciling entries.
- Supervising the day to day operations, ensuring speedy completion of transactions.
- Reconciliation of bank accounts, Secured loans, Sundry Debtors & Creditors.
- Monitoring the cash flow and preparing the funds flow statement.
- Effectively handled accounts payable and accounts receivable activities.
- Ensuring compliance with statutory requirements (GST, TDS, VAT etc.)
- Preparing balance sheet, profit and loss, and other financial statements.
- Preparing the final accounts and participating in auditing with CA.

Asst. Manager - Accounts, Cama Motors Pvt Ltd., August 2017 - April 2018

Responsibilities:

- Checking sales NFA (Note for Approval) report including passed out different schemes.
- Create sales invoice & booking purchase with tax compliances.
- Follow with finance department for customer's payments.
- Reconciliation of bank accounts, Secured loans, Sundry Debtors & Creditors.
- Ensuring compliance with statutory requirements (TDS & TCS)
- Preparing GST Data and Liability and filling the returns co-ordinate with CFO.
- Prepares and records asset, liability, revenue, and expenses entries by compiling and analyzing account information.
- Maintains and balances subsidiary accounts by verifying, allocating, posting, reconciling transactions; resolving discrepancies.
- Maintains general ledger by transferring subsidiary accounts; preparing a trial balance; reconciling entries.
- Summarizes financial status by collecting information; preparing balance sheet, profit and loss, and other statements.

 Completes external audit by analyzing and scheduling general ledger accounts; providing information for auditors.

Asst. Manager - Accounts & Finance, Pandit Ventures Pvt. Ltd., May 2011 - July 2017

Responsibilities:

- Supervising the preparations of accounts of the organization, on time and accurately and undertaking reconciliation.
- Ensuring compliance with statutory requirements (TDS, VAT, Service Tax, etc.)
- Preparing the final accounts and participating in auditing with CA.
- Monitoring the cash flow and preparing the funds flow statement.
- Effectively handled accounts payable and accounts receivable activities.
- Supervising the day to day operations, ensuring speedy completion of transactions and managing bank accounts.
- Actively contributing to various development activities of the organization.

Achievements:

• Got Promotion from Sr. Accountant to Asst. Manager – Account & Finance, due to take all account responsibilities.

Accountant, Gujarat Syscom Technologies Pvt. Ltd., May 2008 - May 2011

Responsibilities:

- Scheduling the accounts payable trial balance, rent, prepaid expenses, debtors & creditors ledger scrutiny, pre paid, loans & salary advances on a monthly basis
- Planned and managed bank accounts, conducted bank reconciliation and handled all basic accounting functions for the organization.
- Ensuring compliance with statutory requirements (TDS, VAT, Service Tax, etc.)
- Monthly Financial report & other related reports.
- Analyzed debtors and implemented control measures to ensure adequate availability of funds; also ensured judicious payment of vendor invoices.
- Scrutinized all the vouchers and updated the account books, processed and dispatched.
- Communicated with clients for collection of past dues & regarding queries.
- Managed financial departments with responsibility for Budgets, Forecasting, Payroll, Accounts Payable and Receivable.
- To co-ordinate with auditor in annual audit.
- To co-ordinate with HR Department for making of Salary Statements.

Achievements:

Promoted from Accounts Executive to Accountant for efficient performance during the tenure.

Account Assistant, Adluna Color Co., May 2003 – May 2008

Responsibilities:

- Check & feed all Accounting entries & generate sales invoice.
- Responsible for Bank Balance & reconciliation of all firms
- TDS, VAT & Service Tax Calculation (Monthly, Quarterly and Annually).
- Preparation and follow up of bills receivables after invoicing.
- Ensuring that all payments are made to suppliers within the time frame.

EDUCATION

- **Bachelor of Commerce**, Gujarat University, 2006
- PG Diploma in IRPM, Bhartiya Vidhya Bhavan (Bhavan's Rajendra Prasad Institute), 2008.
- **Software Programming**, ITI Kubernagar, 2002
- Tally & MS Office, Tenure Computer Academy, Maninagar

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 7 July, 1984

Marital Status: Married

Gender: Male

Languages Known: English, Gujarati, Hindi